Konstantinos Giannousis

kgiann at di.uoa.gr

Mob +30 693 2769571 **Home** +30 210 5692976

Address 14 Cheimarras Str, 18122, Korydallos, Athens, Greece

Skype kgiann78

Personal website https://kgiann78.github.io

Github https://github.com/kgiann78

LinkedIn https://gr.linkedin.com/in/constantine-yannoussis-8126b813

OBJECTIVE

Personal aim is to focus in a carrier as a software engineer or at a position that deals with new technologies, communications and IT. In general I am willing to collaborate at every level to create mutual benefits.

SYNOPSIS

Software engineer at Centre of Automation of Combat Systems (CACS) of the Ministry of Defence (Hellenic Navy) with experience of more than 7 years in C4SRI surveillance systems in **Microsoft .NET** and **Java 8**. Also solid knowledge of telecommunications' systems with more than 15 years experience.

Also, I have been a software engineer and associate researcher at the ATHENA Research Centre and member of the Madgik group (http://www.madgik.di.uoa.gr/people/giannousis) of the University of Athens since 2014.

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Ministry of Defence, Hellenic Navy, Athens, Greece, 2015 - Present

Software Engineer at Centre of Automation of Combat Systems (CACS)

- Backend software engineer of the C4SRI National Surveillance System in Java 8
- Full-stack developer of the C4SRI Distribution System in .NET
- Full-stack developer of the Naval Tactical Simulator in .NET

ATHENA Research Centre — 2016 - 2018

- Backend Software engineer at the OpenMinTeD project (http://openminted.eu)
 - Responsible for the Content Connector Services API in Java 8
 - Implement the Content Connector module for the OpenAIRE project (http://openaire.eu)

ATHENA Research Centre - 2014 - 2016

- Backend Software engineer at the ESPAS project (http://espas.eu/orbis/espas/)
 - Responsible for the Wrapper Services API providing REST and Web services in Java 7

Ministry of Defence, Hellenic Navy, Athens, Greece, 2013 - 2015

Electronics Warfare Warrant Officer at HS KOUNTOURIOTIS

• Manager of the Electronics division at Frigate HS KOUNTOURIOTIS (Kortenaer Class)

Ministry of Defence, Hellenic Navy, Athens, Greece, 2010 - 2013

Software Engineer - Centre of Automation of Combat Systems

- Backend software engineer in projects C4SRI National Surveillance System in .NET
- Full-stack in project Naval Tactical Simulator in .NET

Freelancer Software Developer - 2009 — 2010

 \bullet Web platforms and sites with PHP and MySQL. Hands on Joomla and Wordpress.

Ministry of Defence, Hellenic Navy, Athens, Greece, 2006 - 2010

Senior Chief PO Electronics Technician at Frigate HS ADRIAS

· Leader of the communications and electronics team at Frigate HS ADRIAS (Kortenaer Class)

Ministry of Defence, Hellenic Navy, Athens, Greece, 2001 - 2006

Chief/Senior Chief PO Electronics Technician - Defence Equipment and Support

· Leader of the VHF/UHF team of Electronic Telecommunications

Ministry of Defence, Hellenic Navy, Athens, Greece, 1998 - 2001

PO Electronics Technician at Frigate HS AIGAION

• Technician of telecommunications team of Electronics division at Frigate HS AIGAION (Kortenaer Class)

SPECIALTIES

- Oracle JAVA 7 & JAVA 8 Desktop, Web Applications and Microservices using Spring, Spring MVC, RESTful services, Web Services, Vaadin, GWT, Maven
- Microsoft C# .NET Desktop and Web Applications (Web API), Windows and Web Services (WCF), SignalR (WebSockets), Service Components, Entity Framework
- Docker creating microservices with Docker Containers and Swarm
- Continuous Integration (CI) with Jenkins and Archiva
- Hadoop, Hive and Spark with academic experience and as part of my Master Thesis
- Scala and Python with experience in academic projects and as part of my Master thesis
- · Android development with academic experience building an innovative e-commerce application
- · Angular/Javascript and HTML/CSS with experience in academic projects and as part of my C4SRI projects at CACS
- Databases SQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL. Also noticeable experience in Solr and elasticsearch
- Application Services IIS, Jetty, Apache Tomcat and Glassfish
- C++ / C Research and academic projects
- more like Joomla, WordPress, Text Latex

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

- University of Athens, Athens, Greece MSc in Computer Science, 2018
- University of Athens, Athens, Greece BSc in Computer Science, 2014
- Naval Academy of Petty Officers, Athens, Greece Diploma in Electronics, 1998

CERTIFICATES

- Microsoft Certified Professional Microsoft Certifications
- Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) Cisco Career Certifications
- Certified Network Administrator HAGS (Hellenic Army General Staff)
- Certified Software Development Professional HAGS (Hellenic Army General Staff)

LANGUAGES

- Greek (Native language)
- Certificate of Proficiency in English (Council of Europe Level C2) University of Cambridge
- Certificazione alla lingua Italiana (Livello B1 CELI 2) Universita per stranieri Perugia

ADDITIONAL QUALIFICATIONS

- I have participated at the **SETE Tourism Crowdhackathon** (http://crowdhackathon.com/tourism/) with team "transitrush" where we presented an innovative dining-ordering application suitable for tourists that want to try local cuisines.
- · Awarded for the Naval Tactical Simulator from the Chief of the Hellenic Navy General Staff.

PERSONAL ACTIVITIES

When not coding, I am spending time with family or enjoying running, urban and trail, participating in several events including two marathons (Authentic Marathon of Athens). Conquering the distance is one thing but conquering the mountains is awesome! Cooking is my other next big love and most of the time it is becoming a necessity.

I am devoted to my relationships (my family and child, friends and colleagues) and I enjoy having fun with the people that surrounds me. As a team spirit and easy-going person and it is easy for me to adapt to different conditions and situations.